# Arthur Marmin Curriculum Vitae

# DOCTORAL RESEARCH

# "Rational models optimized exactly for solving signal processing problems" [link]

My research interest is in convex optimization and polynomial optimization and their application to signal processing.

- · I have worked on the application of Lasserre's hierarchy on several signal processing problems where structures can be leveraged to alleviate the computational complexity.
- I have developed algorithms to solve large-scale SDP problems.
- · I have studied the connection between polynomial optimization, tensor decomposition and the moment problem.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

FEBRUARY 2021 — NOW

Signals and Communication Team, IRIT, Toulouse Post-doctoral Researcher

APR IL 2015 — APR IL 2017

Industrial Technology Research Institute, Taiwan Research Engineer

I worked at the System and Architecture Design department:

- · I modelled the power consumption and performance of embedded GPU and wrote OpenGL and Vulkan benchmarks.
- · I took part in the development of a collaborative software platform for SoC, EDA and IP designers to perform early power and performance analysis and validation. The software is based on SystemC/TLM hardware model and a modified version of Qemu to run Android.
- I implemented image rendering techniques on FPGA to reduce the motion-to-photon delay inside virtual reality devices.

JULY — SEPTEMBER 2012

TeamWork Vietnam, Vietnam

SAP administrator

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

SPRING SEMESTER 2020

CentraleSupélec, France Optimization  $(2^{nd} year)$ 

OCTOBER 2017 — JUNE 2020

CentraleSupélec, France

Reinforcement classes in mathematics

FALL SEMESTER 2014

National Chiao Tung University, Taiwan Embedded System Design (Graduate class)

ENSEEIHT, 2 rue Camichel, 31000 Toulouse,

Bureau F202

(+33) 7 69 96 86 40 arthur.marmin@irit.fr

https://www.arthurmarmin.github.io

## **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy in Signal Processing DEC. 2020 Centre de Vision Numérique Advisors: Jean-Christophe Pesquet, Marc Castella Université Paris-Saclay, CentraleSupélec OCT. 2017 Master of Science JAN. 2015 Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Advisor: Shiao-Li Tsao Thesis: Design and Implementation of an Embedded GPU Simulator National Chiao Tung University, Taiwan SEP. 2013 **Engineer Diploma in Telecommunication** JAN. 2015

Télécom SudParis SEP. 20II

## COMPUTER SKILLS

C++, Assembly Languages, Python, PROGRAMMING

LISP

HARDWARE DESIGN Verilog, VHDL, SystemC, TLM

OpenGL, OpenCL, Qt, mlpack,

Linux kernel

Matlab, GloptiPoly, Tensorlab, SOFTWARE

Xilinx Vivado Design suite, Git, Doxygen, Emacs

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

FRENCH Mother tongue Fluent, working operational **ENGLISH** Good working knowledge MANDARIN Used in daily life and working environment Good working knowledge GERMAN

# **EXTRA INFORMATION**

- · I have reviewed articles for IEEE Transactions on Signal Pro-
- · I was a visitor at Gdansk University of Technology under the supervision of Anna Jezierska in January 2020.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Journal articles

- 1. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, Jean-Christophe Pesquet, and Laurent Duval. Sparse signal reconstruction for nonlinear models via piecewise rational optimization. *Signal Process.*, 179:107835, February 2021. doi: 10.1016/j.sigpro.2020.107835.
- 2. Arthur Marmin, Anna Jezierska, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. Global Optimization for Recovery of Clipped Signals Corrupted With Poisson-Gaussian Noise. *IEEE Signal Process. Lett.*, 27:970–974, May 2020. doi: 10.1109/lsp.2020.2998699.
- 3. Marc Castella, Jean-Christophe Pesquet, and Arthur Marmin. Rational Optimization for Nonlinear Reconstruction with Approximate  $\ell_0$  Penalization. *IEEE Trans. Signal Process.*, 67(6):1407–1417, March 2019. doi: 10.1109/tsp.2018.2890065.

# Conference articles

- 4. Elie Leroy, Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Laurent Duval. Weight Identification Through Global Optimization in a New Hysteretic Neural Network Model. In *Proc. Int. Conf. Acoust. Speech Signal Process.* IEEE, June 2021. doi: 10.1109/icassp39728.2021. 9413383.
- 5. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. Globally Optimizing Owing to Tensor Decomposition. In *Proc. European Signal Processing Conference*, pages 990–994. IEEE, January 2021.
- 6. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. Robust Reconstruction with Nonconvex Subset Constraints: A Polynomial Optimization Approach. In *IEEE Int. Workshop Mach. Learn. Signal Process.* IEEE, September 2020. doi: 10.1109/mlsp49062.2020.9231524.
- 7. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. A Moment-Based Approach for Guaranteed Tensor Decomposition. In *Proc. Int. Conf. Acoust. Speech Signal Process.*, pages 3927–3931. IEEE, May 2020. doi: 10.1109/icassp40776.2020.9054186.
- 8. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. Detecting the Rank of a Symmetric Tensor. In *Proc. European Signal Processing Conference*, pages 1–5. IEEE, September 2019. doi: 10.23919/eusipco.2019.8902781.
- 9. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. Sparse Signal Reconstruction with a Sign Oracle. In *Proc. Signal Processing with Adaptive Sparse Structured Representations (SPARS) workshop*, July 2019.
- 10. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, and Jean-Christophe Pesquet. How to Globally Solve Non-convex Optimization Problems Involving an Approximate  $\ell_0$  Penalization. In *Proc. Int. Conf. Acoust. Speech Signal Process.*, pages 5601–5605. IEEE, May 2019. doi: 10.1109/icassp.2019.8683692.
- II. Arthur Marmin, Marc Castella, Jean-Christophe Pesquet, and Laurent Duval. Signal Reconstruction from Sub-sampled and Non-linearly Distorted Observations. In *Proc. European Signal Processing Conference*, pages 1970–1974. IEEE, September 2018. doi: 10.23919/eusipco.2018.8553174.
- 12. Arthur Marmin, Chun-Hung Lai, Haruyuki Tago, Hsun-Lun Huang, and Juin-Ming Lu. Architecture agnostic energy model for GPU-based design. In 2016 International Symposium on VLSI Design, Automation and Test (VLSI-DAT). IEEE, April 2016. doi: 10.1109/vlsi-dat.2016.7482557.